Guide to the Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program records 1969-2002.
Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program records 1969-2002
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Cornell University Library
Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program records 1969-2002.
21-24-3292
Cornell Cooperative Extension Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program.
10.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Photographs, Subject Files, Reports, Videotapes, Slides.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes reports, correspondence, in-service projects, subject files, photographs, videotapes, slides, and curriculum material pertaining to this federal nutrition program (EFNEP). Sponsored by Cornell Cooperative Extension, including records on WIC.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes reports, correspondence, in-service projects, subject files, photographs, videotapes, slides, and curriculum material pertaining to this federal nutrition program (EFNEP. Sponsored by Cornell Cooperative Extension including records on WIC.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Cooperative Extension.; Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children (U.S.)
Subjects:
Nutrition extension work--New York (State).; Nutrition policy.; Children--Nutrition.; Nutritional Sciences--Study and teaching.; Curriculum planning.
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.; Slides (photographs).; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
See also collections #21-24-1975, Cornell University Cooperative Extension Records; #29-4-2733 Division of Nutritional Sciences Cooperative Extension Nutrition Program Records; and #29-1-3247, Division of Nutritional Sciences Records for related material.
SERIES LIST
Series I. County (Data) Year End Reports
Boxes: 1-4
Series II. Updates and Inservices
Box: 5
Series III. Correspondence
Box: 6
Series IV. Narrative Reports, Progress Reports-Issues by Topic
Boxes: 7-9
Series V. Conferences and Workshops
Boxes: 8, 9
Series VI. Publications and Resources
Boxes: 8-13
Series VII. Slides, Photographs, and Videos
Boxes: 7, 9, 10
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. County (Data) Year End Reports
  - Albany through Erie County Year End Reports (Box 1, Folder 1-17)
  - Essex through Oneida County Year End Reports (Box 2, Folder 1-15)
  - Onondaga through Suffolk County Year End Reports (Box 3, Folder 1-18)
  - Sullivan through Yates County Year End Reports (Box 4, Folder 1-9)
  - EFNEP New York State Report (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - EFNEP State Reports Excluding New York City, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11-15)
  - EFNEP Combined New York City Report, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - EFNEP New York City Reports, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
- Series II. Updates and Inservices
  - Inservice, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Inservice and EFNEP Review, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Inservice, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Inservice, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Inservice, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Update, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Success Stories, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Planning NTA Conference, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - R andR transparencies, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Inservice, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Update, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Inservice, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Inservice, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Update, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Inservice, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - In-depth study week course, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Connecting the E's - Extension, Empowerment, EFNEP, 1989-11 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Food Decisions concerning implementation of dietary guideline - Limited Income Families and Youth, 1991-06 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Families and Food: New Directions for Family Programming, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Update, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Update, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Inservice, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Update, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Update, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Update, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Update, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Update, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Update, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Update, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Fall Update for Nutrition Educators, 2005-11 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - General Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Series IV. Narrative Reports,Progress Reports,Issues by Topic
  - Newspaper articles, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper articles, 1970-1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper articles, 1975-1990 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Historical files, no date (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Progress Report, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Narrative Report, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Progress Report, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Narrative Report, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Narrative Report, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Narrative Report, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Narrative Reports and results, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Narrative Reports, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Narrative and results, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Narrative Reports, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Narrative Reports, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Narrative and results, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Progress Reports, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Narrative and results, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Narrative and results, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Narrative and Progress Reports, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Narrative and Progress Reports, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Narrative Report, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Task Force for the Poor Report - Pre-EFNEP, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Proposal-New York Medical College, East Harlem Health Council, Cornell University, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - "Effectiveness of Paraprofessionals in Working with Low Income Families", 1969 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - East Harlem Program and Budget, proposals, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Progress Report on Nutrition Education Program - Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1970-02 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - EFNEP memos, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Project FIND, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - EFNEP Reports, 1969-1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - EFNEP Reports and Summaries, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - WIC Program Information, 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Calendars, 1970-1989 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Sample EFNEP Calendars (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - 4-H EFNEP, 1970-1990 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - EFNEP Notebook - all sites info, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Recruitment and Selection of Aides, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Blau Report, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - National Food and Nutrition Education Program, 1970-05 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Competencies for Aids As a Teacher of Food and Nutrition, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Situation, Scope and Priorities and Guide for Comprehensive EFNEP Unit Review, 1974-04 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Information on Population, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Plan of Work, 1975-1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - USDA Program Audit, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Narrative Report, 1970-1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Reports on Program Impact, 1975-1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Program Management Materials, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - EFNEP History, 1978-1985 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - USDA EFNEP Evaluations, Reports, 1978-1984 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Framework for Evaluation of the Nutrition Education and Training Program, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Review Implications for New York State, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - EFNEP History, Purpose and the Intergovernmental System-By Jane McGonigal, 1980-05 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - County Phase Out - Future Plans, 1980-1989 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - EFNEP Team Minutes, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Competencies and Surveys, 1982-1992 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - An Assessment of the Objectives and Implementation of the 4-H EFNEP Summary, 1982-04 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - EFNEP Review, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Breastfeeding Education Program-lesson plans, handouts, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - EFNEP-The Adolescent Confronts Adulthood-by Marian Rauch, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - EFNEP Record and Recording System, 1985-10 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - EFNEP Innovative Projects-Sponsored by Virginia Cooperative Extension Service, 1985-11 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Factor in the Life Patterns of Paraprofessionals: EFNEP Aides in New York State, 1985-06 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Technical Proposal - Integrated Multi-Media Nutrition Education Campaign, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - EFNEP Team Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - EFNEP Team Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - EFNEP Records and Reporting System Agreement, 1986-01 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Status of EFNEP, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Extension's Food, Nutrition and Health-Program Emphases and Outcome Indicators for years 1988-1991, 1986-07 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - "Maximizing Independence: Nutrition for Seniors in Transition", 1988-07 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Assessment of Migrant EFNEP, Wayne County, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 54)
    Fall
  - Opportunities for Nutrition Education Through Cornell Cooperative Extension in Metropolitan Areas, 1988-09 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "An Evaluation of the 'Target What You Eat' Curriculum in EFNEP's Upper Manhattan Site: It's Effect on Children's Knowledge and Behaviour Change" by Julia Plotnik, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Adult EFNEP - by Muriel Brink, 1989-02 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Conceptualizations and Use of Power in the EFNEP of Cornell Cooperative Extension - Course Project, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - EFNEP System Analysis Report, July 1990 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Nutrition Guidelines for Sports, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 4-H, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - County/Site History of EFNEP, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Volunteer Development in EFNEP, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - EFNEP New York Youth Component-Survey of Agents, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - "Building Blocks for Toddlers" grant application, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - EFNEP Cornell Cooperative Extension Resources, 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Committee, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Division of Nutrition Sciences Strategic Plan, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Impact Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - EFNEP Planning for the Future, 1996-01 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Area/Regional EFNEP Process Evaluation Guide, 1997-05 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - EFNEP Extension Educator Notebook, 1998-11 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - EFNEP Performance Plan, Guidelines, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - EFNEP special grants, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - EFNEP special grants, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - EFNEP special grants, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - EFNEP special grants, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - EFNEP special projects, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Grant opportunity - Tompkins County, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - ERS history (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of Achievement (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Methods (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Promotional brochures and articles (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Checklist for Aide Visit (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Quality of Teaching (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - County Site EFNEP Implementation - Implementation of Other CCE Nutrition Programs (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Working With Groups (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Guidelines/Policies (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - NTA Position Descriptions IIIIII Generic Originals and Performance Appraisal (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Food Factory Lesson Series for Youth (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Evaluations (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Food Labeling (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 24 Hour Recall: Instructions (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Referrals (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Graduation (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Progression Record (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lesson Topics (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Aide Management Record Keeping (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Training (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - EFNEP In-depth site reviews and process (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Forms A - K (packets) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Marketing (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Youth Resources (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Volunteers (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Pilot Testing (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Lesson Planning (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Appraisal Forms (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Guidelines for Adult and Youth Group Work (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Supervision (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - NTA Competency Tests (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - History - Record and Reporting System (R and R) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Impact - Various Counties (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - General Information (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Notebook on Communications: EFNEP Narrative Reports (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Series V. Conferences and Workshops
  - Pilot Workshop on Volunteers in EFNEP (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Conference on Low Income Families - Pre- EFNEP, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Workshops/Conferences, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Workshops/Conferences, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Workshops/Conferences, 1973-1978 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Reaching Out to Minority Populations: Educating Ourselves to Meet the Needs of Others" - talk presented by Janet Fitchen at EFNEP Conference, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - EFNEP 5th Anniversary (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Focus on the Future Conference-summary sheet, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - International Conference on Nutrition-World Declaration, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - EFNEP 20th Anniversary, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - EFNEP 20th and 25th Anniversary (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Youth Workshop, 1995-04 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - "Building Bridges to Better Health and Fitness", 2004-06 (Box 17, Folder 25)
- Series VI. Publications and Resources
  - Working with Families (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - When You're the Teacher (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Nutrient Information Resources (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - EFNEP Makes a Difference (brochure) (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Samples of Resources developed by EFNEP Staff (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Food Labeling, 1960-1979 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Helping Low Income Homemakers: Programs and Evaluations, 1969-11 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Housing/Housekeeping, 1970-1989 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - EFNEP Aide Handouts, 1970-1979 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - EFNEP County Mini-Lessons, no date (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Lesson Outlines, 1970-1989 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Various EFNEP brochures, flyers, memos, 1970-2002 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Target What you Eat - Resource, 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - A Plea for Better Understanding, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Nutrition Activities for Day Camps, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The Expanded Nutrition Education Program- color slide set text, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Values Clarification Strategies- Examples of Nutrition Educators", 1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - A Community Study of Food Habits and Sociocultural Factors of Selected Families Participating in the East Harlem Nutrition Education Program, 1972-06 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program- Food Habits and Socio-Cultural Factors- Number 4, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program- Report, 1973-06 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program- An Exploration of Dietary Practices- Number 1, 1973-09 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program- Methods and Procedures for Biochemical and Dietary Assessment - Number 2, 1973-11 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program Progress Report, 1973-11 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program- Dietary and Biochemical Assessment of Women in a High-risk Obstetric Clinic- Number 3, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program- Influence of EFNEP Aides on Dietary Practices of Pregnant Women- Number 6, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program-Final Report, 1975-02 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - East Harlem Nutrition Education Program- A study of Infant Feeding Practices- Number 5, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Expanded Nutrition Education Program- Guidelines for Youth Component, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - EFNEP Accomplishments and Future Needs, 1975-07 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - How EFNEP Helps People-Case Studies in New York State, 1975-10 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "A Programmed Guide: The Uses of the Nutrimeter and Related Resources" by Jill Randell, 1976-04 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - "Concerns of the Aging Nutrition and Health Related Statistical Data", 1976-01 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "Influence of EFNEP on Infant Children in East Harlem" and "A Study of Infant Feeding Practices in East Harlem", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "Milk Consumption of Families Living in East Harlem" and Role of EFNEP Aides in Improving Diets of Pregnant Women", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - The Funmobile- An Innovative Nutrition Education Program, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Working with Families through EFNEP" A guide for cooperative extension agents and aides, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Food Purchasing Patterns- Food Expenditures and Nutrient Profiles Among New York State EFNEP Households, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Food Buying, 1978-1989 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - EFNEP-Historical and Statistical Profile, 1979-03 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Supervision and Management of EFNEP, 1979-10 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Guide for Comprehensive EFNEP Unit Review, 1979-10 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - New Opportunities- EFNEP and 4H Youth, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Nutrition Education: A Neighborhood Approach, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - "Nutrition Activities Preschoolers and Parents", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - New York State - Food Stamp Pilot Project Proposal, Reports and Materials, 1979-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - County Mini-lessons for New York State EFNEP, 1980-1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "Try Something New"- Martha Mapes and Gail Keown, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Early Childhood Educator's Nutrition Handbook", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Food for the Family-Lesson Plans, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Aides' Guide to the Progression Model and Supervising Agent's Guide to the Progression Model, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Teaching and Applying Educational Principles in EFNEP, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 21A)
  - "The Food Factory"- nutrition series for youth, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - New York State EFNEP/Food Stamp Pilot Project- Communicating Nutrition, 1981-03 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Fun Times With Food - Resource, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography-EFNEP-USDA, 1981-07 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Effect of Environmental Changes on Food Consumption and Nutrient Intake Among Puerto Rican Families, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Resources for Adult Leaders in Group Programs for School-Aged Children, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - EFNEP Initial Aide Training- by Linda Proctor, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - EFNEP Initial Aide Training- by Linda Proctor, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - "The Aide and the Homemaker"- How to achieve an effective Aide Homemaker Relationship in EFNEP- by Janet Fitchen, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Its Your Move, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - EFNEP Calendar, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - EFNEP Agent Notebook, 1983-1993 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - A Guide to Evaluation in the EFNEP Program, February 1983 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Breastfeeding Education Program, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - "New Opportunities for Youth- Working together with 4-H and EFNEP", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - EFNEP Audio Cassette Programs, April 1983 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - EFNEP Brochure, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - New York State EFNEP/Food Stamp Pilot Program, August 1983 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - EFNEP Tapes (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Expanded Food and Nutrition Program- Guide to Program Management and Supervision, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - More For Your Money, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - New York State EFNEP/Food Stamp Pilot Project- An Alternative Teaching Method, 1985-07 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - EFNEP Makes a Difference, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - A 4-H EFNEP Effort to Involve Youth From Low Income Families in 4-H via Volunteer Leadership-Report and Appendices, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - EFNEP- Task Force Report, 1987-12 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Focus on Food Preparation Principles, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "Structures of Misery: Hunger in Our Communities"- An Investigation of Hunger in Oneida, New York- Survey ad Report done by John Zogby Group, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - EFNEP Studies of Program Delivery, Length of Participation and Retention of Knowledge and Practice, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - EFNEP News (No.1-12), 1987-1995 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - EFNEP brochures in English and Spanish, 1990-1999 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Food and Nutrition Basics, 1990-1999 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "The New Mother Hubbard's Cupboard"- cookbook, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Introduction to EFNEP: A Plan for New Agents- by Margaret Day, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Fat Facts - English and Spanish, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Keeping Food Safe to Eat, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - What is EFNEP?, 1990-10 (Box 10)
  - Criteria for a Quality EFNEP (revised 1984 and 1992); Leadership of EFNEP (1990), 1990-1999 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - "Fun Times with Food", 1991 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Enhanced EFNEP Record and Reporting Manual, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Enhanced EFNEP Record and Reporting Manual for Nutrition Teaching Assistants, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Enhanced EFNEP Record and Reporting System, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Enhanced EFNEP Record and Reporting Manual, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - "Nutritional Health of School-Aged Children in Upstate New York", 1991 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - EFNEP- Participation Facts, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Criteria for a Quality EFNEP, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Initial Education Curriculum for Nutrition Teaching Assistants, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Initial Education Curriculum for Nutrition Teaching Assistants, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Initial Education Curriculum for NTAs- Agent Manual, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Pre and Post Assessment- Nutrition Teaching Assistants, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - "Safety and Food Excellence"- A Program for Food Safety Leaders, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - "Taxi- Taking Adults and Youth into Expanded Involvement"- State Training Volunteer Management, 1993-06 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Training Parent Educators- Introductory Materials, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Training Parent Educators- Introductory Materials, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Training Parent Educators- Introductory Materials (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Performance Review Worksheets for Nutrition Teaching Assistants (NTAs), 1993 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Reducing Risks for New York Communities- leaflet, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - 4-H EFNEP Materials, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - "Retention of Nutrition Knowledge and Practices Among Adult EFNEP Participants" Murial Brink and Jeffrey Sobal, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - EFNEP- New York State Participation Facts, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - "For Goodness Sake!"- Videotape Series, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Curriculum Material, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - EFNEP - New York State Participation Facts, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 34)